# LUXI HUANG

@ lucy96akane@gmail.com

**(**224)999-3312

% https://luxi-huang.github.io/portfolio/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/luxi-huang-765076137

**♥** Chicago, IL

#### **SUMMARY**

Seeking for 2020 Summer Intern position in robotics area.

Master Student in Robotics Major with strong **programming** and **mathematical** skills. 5+ years of hands-on robot development experience including **motion planing**, **navigation**, **control system**, and **search algorithm**.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Northwestern University (NU), Evanston, IL

Expected Dec.2020

Master of Robotics

University of Maryland (UMD), College Park, MD

Dec.2018

Bachelor of Science Mechanical Engineering; Mathematics

#### **SKILLS**

Primary Operating System: Linux

Robot Skills: ROS, Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Motion Planing, Microcontroller, Bayesian Filters,

Version Control (Git), Search Algorithm

Programming Languagege: C/C++, Python, MATLAB/SimuLink

Mechanical Engineering: SolidWorks, ANSYS, CNC, Laser Cutter, FEA, UG, Design Process

Data Analysis: SAS

# SELECTED PROJECTS

# Robot Navigation From Scratch on Turtlebot3 - NU

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

- · Developed 2D kinematics and navigation library in C++ for differential drive robots
- $\cdot$  Wrote circular feature detection algorithm for **LiDAR** scanner and implemented a landmark-based **EKF SLAM** algorithm
- · Develop system on **Docker** and Implement Turtlebot3 **navigation** using **ROS** in C++ as the central platform.

# ReThink Robot Build Lego - NU

Step. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- · Develop a system to **control** a Baxter (Rethink Robotics) to build Lego
- · Programmed whole node on 7-DOF arm **trajectory algorithm** using **ROS MoveIt** (in **Python**) to accomplish **motion planning** and obstacle avoiding, and control the force on grippers

### Quadrupedal Bio-inspired Robotics Project - UMD

Jan. 2018 - May 2018

- · Collaborated with a group of 3 students to design, build, and test quadrupedal bio-inspired newt robotics
- · Analyzed gait and implement Inverse Kinematics to control robotic navigation in MATLAB on Arduino
- · Created full technical drawing of robot components on **Solidworks**
- · Designed and constructed **circuitry** for robotics

## Internet Communicating Vehicles - UMD

Sept.2018 - Dec.2018

- · Designed, build, and assembly vehicles robot to communicate and motion control with internet or joysticks.
- · Programmed in **Python** on **Raspberry Pi** Board to control **actuators** and robot motion.
- · Generated dynamic web page for Pi communication and data transferring.

# WORK EXPERIENCE:

### Research Assistant, The Sensor and Actuator Lab - UMD

Dec. 2017 - Dec.2018

- · Designed metamaterial sonar to strongly magnified acoustic signals
- · Designed and built a **wheel robotic** to tracking moved barriers by sending and receiving acoustic signals through metamaterial sonar
- · Created and printed **3-D** components of robotic and metamaterial sonar.
- · Code on Launch-F28379D **DSP** board in **C** to control robot **navigation** tracking barriers though sending and receiving acoustic signals with **PID** control.

### MATLAB tutor - UMD

Feb. 2016 - May 2016

· Tutored undergraduate students in MATLAB for calculus, differential equation, and linear algebra courses